Finding a new job isn’t always easy.
找新工作并不总是一帆风顺的。
You search for a suitable vacancy, send in an application form and if that goes well, you might be invited for an interview.
你要寻找合适的职位空缺，提交申请表，如果一切顺利，可能会收到面试邀请。
For some, this is when the panic sets in – you’re going to be faced by a panel of strangers who’ll fire difficult questions at you, and you’ll have to actually prove yourself.
对有些人来说，这时恐慌就会袭来——你要面对一群陌生人组成的面试小组，他们会抛出刁钻的问题，而你必须实实在在地证明自己的能力。
But how would you feel if, instead of being asked why you want the job, you’re asked to stand up and dance?!
但如果面试官不问你“为什么想要这份工作”，反而让你站起来跳舞，你会是什么感受？
From the perspective of a company, it wants to hire the right person because they can make a big difference to the success of the organisation.
从公司的角度来看，它希望招聘到合适的人，因为这些人能对组织的成功产生重大影响。
It therefore needs to test a candidate in the most appropriate way to discover how suitable he or she may be.
因此，公司需要以最恰当的方式测试候选人，以了解其是否胜任岗位。
A good interview process should involve rigorous screening of job applicants and effective questions that every applicant gets asked.
一个完善的面试流程应包括对求职者的严格筛选，以及向每位求职者提出有效的问题。
But that’s not always the case.
但实际情况并非总是如此。
Alison Green is an author and creator of the workplace advice column 'Ask a Manager'.
艾莉森·格林是职场建议专栏《咨询经理》（Ask a Manager）的作者和创始人。
She told the BBC that some companies “give their interviewers little or no training and often leave them completely on their own when it comes to figuring out what to ask job candidates.”
她向英国广播公司表示，一些公司“给面试官的培训很少或根本没有，在决定该问求职者什么问题时，往往让他们完全自行决定”。
She mentions that some interviewers are too casual and some focus on building a good rapport and end up hiring the candidate they just ‘clicked with’, regardless of their skills and abilities.
她提到，有些面试官过于随意，有些则专注于建立融洽的关系，最终聘用了那些与他们“合拍”的候选人，而忽视了其实际技能和能力。
An inexperienced interviewer may think it’s clever to ask ‘if you were an animal, what kind would you be?’
缺乏经验的面试官可能会觉得问“如果你是一种动物，你会是什么动物？”很巧妙。
That has been asked, Alison Green says, but in reality this has no connection with the job.
艾莉森·格林说，确实有人被问过这个问题，但实际上这与工作毫无关联。
And there have been inappropriate requests, such as one job seeker being asked to show the interviewer the inside of her handbag to demonstrate how organised she was.
还有些不合时宜的要求，比如有求职者被要求向面试官展示手提包内部，以证明自己多么有条理。
Talking of inappropriate, the BBC heard from a number of people who were surprised by the questions they were asked in an interview.
说到不合时宜，英国广播公司还收到了不少人的反馈，他们都对面试中被问到的问题感到惊讶。
Mature student Kevin Helton said that "the interviewer asked, 'you used to be in the Army, how many people have you killed?'”
成年学生凯文·赫尔顿说：“面试官问我，‘你以前当过兵，杀过多少人？’”
But as Alison Green points out, while a candidate might feel at the mercy of an interviewer, they are able to question why they’re being asked something, and while the interviewer might be making judgements, the candidate can also make their own judgement and decide if this is really the career move they want to make!
但正如艾莉森·格林所指出的，虽然候选人可能会觉得自己受制于面试官，但他们有权询问被问此类问题的原因。而且，面试官在做出判断的同时，候选人也可以自行判断，决定这是否真的是自己想要的职业变动！